Abhinath Jadhav

Software Engineer (JAVA/Springboot)

Java Developer with over 2.6+ years of experience in Software Development using Core java and Springboot. Strong Knowledge of Application Development using Agile/Scrum methodology. Experience in working with MySQL, hibernate, and Collection framework. Strong knowledge of working with Stream API, Exception handling, String, and Generics in Java 8. Experience in managing Restful Webservices with springboot.

Core Competencies

- Java 8, Java 11
- · Hibernate, Spring Boot
- Core Java
- String, Array, Collection framework
- MySQL5
- Git.
- JIRA.
- MongDB
- Intellij, STS-4, VS Code.
- · Angular (Basic knowledge),
- HTML and CSS (Basic knowledge)

Contact Information

Mobile:

9503698655

Email / LinkedIn

abhinath.jadhav18@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/abhinath18/

Address:

F106, Nea Apartment, behind TUV India Company, Sus Road, Pune, Maharashtra 411021

Personal Details

Birth Date: 18 Nov 1995

Gender: Male

Marital status: Single Nationality: Indian

Languages: English, Hindi, Marathi

Academic History

Graduation

Aeronautical Engineering
June 2018 | ADCET, Ashta, Sangali

Polytechnic

Mechanical Engineering

July 2015 | Gaurishankar Poly., Satara

Secondary School Certificate

State board, Maharashtra

June 2011 | SSG Highscool, Kole

Work Experience in JAVA

2 Years and 6 months

R Systems, Noida | May 2022 - Present

ProInsigh and ProAct Application | Client - Moblize

- The application is used by companies that are working on drilling crude oil wells.
- It was a real-time drilling analytics application designed to simplify planning, daily operations, post-well analysis, & reporting workflows, provide greater insight, and enable clients to make quicker and more informed decisions.
- It was used to compare the performance of your target well(s) to nearby wells from other operators anonymously down to the same county on key metrics ensuring that you meet or exceed targeted well expectations

Roles and Responsibility

- Producing restful web services using Spring boot with microservices.
- Analyze the program to identify the code changes as per the business requirements.
- Deploying the changes on a development server.
- Debugging production bugs and supporting the running application.
- Testing of code changes on UI.

Sonovision Aetos, Bangalore | April 2020 - May 2022

E-learning | Client - Dassault aviation

- In pilot training, the initial information regarding the different aircraft systems and the working of its mechanisms becomes necessary before training any pilot or ground crew on a particular aircraft in the actual field.
- To fulfill this requirement we designed and developed a full-fledged E-Learning system for pilots and ground crew of Mirage M2K9 and Rafale aircraft for our client.

Roles and Responsibility

- · Producing restful web services Spring boot.
- Analyze the program to identify the code changes as per the business requirements.
- Contributing to all phases of the Software development lifecycle (SDLC).
- Writing well-designed, efficient, and testable code.
- Debugging production bugs and supporting the running application.
- · Ensuring designs comply with specifications.
- Preparing and producing releases of software components.

Training

- Currently learning full stack development with MERN stack with coding ninja's Carer camp professional to improve my skills in the software field.
- Where i'll be learning full stack development with react JS, system design, database, and operating system design.

Strength

- · Working with team
- Creative problem solving
- Time management
- Strong communication skills
- Quick learner.
- Self-learner

Achievements

- Employee of the year 2021 (Sonovision)
- Got opportunity to work on site with dassault aviation at Pune office.

Self project

E-Commerce application

- Developed console-based E-Commerce application.
- In this Admin had the ability to add, update, and delete products.
- Also had the ability to update QTY and the price of the particular product.
- Used core java, JDBC, and MySQL

Profile Summery

- Having experience of 2.1 years in Java and related technologies.
- Use Java/J2EE technologies to develop web applications for client-server environments and add functionalities to existing applications.
- Revamp various Java applications developed with Spring and Hibernate.
- Play a pivotal role as a part of an agile scrum team accountable, developing new applications using the Spring framework.
- Good communication, and collaboration with proficiency at grasping new technical concepts quickly and productively utilizing the same.
- Ability to work both independently and in a collaborative environment
- · Have Strong analytical and multi-tasking skills
- Security Awareness (Spring Security, JWT)
- Worked in a team of web developers, designers, and other IT personnel to meet team goals and improve business outcomes.
- Aware of industry-standard design patterns like Singleton, MVC, and Factory.
- Good knowledge of Advanced and Core Java, Spring, Spring Core, Hibernate, Hibernate Mapping, and Hibernate Cache.
- Good exposure to Software Development and Coding.
- Good with the concepts of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC).
- · Good Experience working in Agile Methodology.
- Exemplary understanding of OOP's concept.
- Exquisite understanding of Collection, Exception handling, String.
- Experience in web application using Springboot.
- Configuring the data source in hibernate configuration file
- Extensional knowledge about ORM & Hibernate concepts like Cache, Session, and Queries.
- Good knowledge of MySQL database.
- Basic knowledge in HTML & CSS.
- Clever in Rest API Services for applications
- Used Git as a version control tool while working on the project

Work Experience in Other technology

1 Year and 7 months

Sonovision Aetos, Bangalore | August 2018 - March 2020

- Worked on some UI technologies like SVG editor (Inkscape),
 Notepad++ for editing the SVG files, also sometimes we have used
 Adobe tools like illustrator and photoshop,
- The UI content was in form of technical information and drawing, and internal flows of aircraft hydraulic and electrical links so our task was to convert that from 9*9 to 16*9 format.

Declaration

I hereby declare that all above-mentioned information is in accordance with fact or truth up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.

Date:		
Place:	Abhinath	Jadha